<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Blog That Works on Home</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A Blog That Works on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a Shiny app with me</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-04-22-build-a-shiny-app-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-04-22-build-a-shiny-app-with-me/</guid>
      <description>Aim and scope The objective of this blog post is to walk through app creation and deployment using Shiny and shiny.io. This is intended to provide a high level overview of the process, but I highly encourage anyone interested in building their own apps to look into the resources compiled here. The shinyapps.io user guide is a very concise document to get anyone started!
 Why should you create an app?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph theory primer</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-07-01-graph-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-07-01-graph-theory/</guid>
      <description>Aim In this blogpost, I will review foundational concepts underlying co-occurrence networks and apply them to visualize a drinking water metagenome dataset.
 Scope The information discussed in the “Background” section is in part a summary of the “Graph Theory for Data Science” workshop series taught by Stanford University PhD student Julia Olivieri, as a part of Women in data science workshop series. Her workshops are available on youtube and consist of the three parts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website content creation nugget 1</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-07-01-content-creation-nugget-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-07-01-content-creation-nugget-1/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: The objective of this post is to reflect on how we write and to set up a template to reuse in future blog posts.
 Tips for blog post writing Writing research papers is not the same as writing academic blogs. The former is more prescriptive, limited to a number of characters, and usually constrained to 4-5 figures and tables (sure, we can go crazy in the supplementary material, but there’s a reason why it’s supplementary … ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-06-28-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-06-28-resources/</guid>
      <description>  This page will be updated continuously to highlight functions, packages, and presentations useful for R users.
It will generally contain a brief description and links to tutorials or vignettes.
If there’s something I’d love for you to learn more about I will create a separate blog post.
Keep an eye out!
Learn R  Visualization  Modeling  Rmarkdown  Shiny  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my webpage - you can do it too!</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-06-25-setting-up-my-webpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-06-25-setting-up-my-webpage/</guid>
      <description>Aim The purpose of this markdown is to generate my own page and document the process for peers in my research group and others.
 Scope In this document I will be following Allison Hill’s Up &amp;amp; running with blogdown in 2021 post. The steps here deviate a bit from her proposed 7 step guide, but I used it as a starting point. I will provide my own commentary and experience deploying a website from R for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
