<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metagenomics on Home</title>
    <link>/categories/metagenomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Metagenomics on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/metagenomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Antimicrobial Resistance in DWS</title>
      <link>/project/p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/p1/</guid>
      <description>Summary     Antimicrobial resistance (AMR) in drinking water has received less attention than its counterparts in the urban water cycle. While culture-based techniques or gene-centric PCR have been used to probe the impact of treatment approaches (e.g., disinfection) on AMR in drinking water, to our knowledge there is no systematic comparison of AMR trait distribution and prevalence between disinfected and disinfectant residual-free drinking water systems. We used metagenomics to assess the associations between disinfectant residuals and AMR prevalence and its host association in full-scale drinking water distribution systems (DWDSs) with and without disinfectant residuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbiological composition in DWS after Maria</title>
      <link>/project/p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/p2/</guid>
      <description>Summary     Loss of basic utilities, such as drinking water and electricity distribution, were sustained for months in the aftermath of Hurricane Maria&amp;rsquo;s (HM) landfall in Puerto Rico (PR) in September 2017. The goal of this study was to assess if there was deterioration in biological quality of drinking water due to these disruptions. This study characterized the microbial composition of drinking water following HM across nine drinking water systems (DWSs) in PR and utilized an extended temporal sampling campaign to determine if changes in the drinking water microbiome were indicative of HM associated disturbance followed by recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
